ice cream season has officially started
and for the last 2 months I have been
piping three protein ice cream recipes
every day to perfect them they take
minutes to prep have 50 g of protein
each and taste identical to their high
calorie counterparts let's get into it
first we will start with the classic
mint chocolate chip unexpectedly using
the right chocolate for this recipe was
quite the challenge for a good chocolate
chip it needs to melt in your mouth when
surrounded by ice cold cream but still
have a nice crunch we will start with a
full bar of highquality semi chocolate
and my favorite during testing was the
geraldi brand you can also use their
baking chips or whatever chocolate bar
you prefer just use
113.5 GS of it we will now double boil
the chocolate to melt it all we have to
do for that is fill a small pot with an
inch of water place a bowl over the pot
and add the chocolate place the pot on
medium heat and once it comes to a
simmer the chocolate will start to melt
you may be wondering why not just use
chocolate that's already made from the
store every chocolate I used in the
testing process was either too hard and
felt like I was chewing on crayons or
the chocolate didn't taste right after
being mixed in the ice cream at that
point for the perfect mint chocolate
chip making our own was the only option
once the chocolate is melted we will add
7 G of peanut oil or any neutral oil you
would like the oil will help soften the
chocolate after it mixes into the frozen
ice cream but will still have a crunch
to it it whisk the chocolate and oil
together until fully combined then line
a small sheet pan with parchment paper
and using gloves and a rubber spatula
pour the chocolate onto the parchment
paper spread out the chocolate until it
is about an eighth of an inch thick and
place in the freezer time to make our
ice cream grab a high-sided container
and add 430 G 1% high protein milk since
no stores carry 1% in Texas I buy a 2%
and fat free and use 215 G of each then
add 4.2 G of vanilla extract and eight
drops of green food coloring to get that
beautiful mint color for the last of the
when ingredients we will add either 12
drops of mccormix or four drops of
Lauren's peppermint extract these both
have slightly different flavor profiles
when it comes to Mint but they are both
delicious if you want a more mellow mint
flavor I would go with mccormix while if
you want a strong mint flavor I would go
with lauran just make sure you measure
in drops or else you will feel like you
are brushing your teeth while eating
this ice cream ESP especially with the
strength of Lauren's extract put that
off to the side and into another cup add
one scoop or 32.4 G of vanilla we
protein 20 G urethral or the sweetener
of your choice a half G of salt and a
half G of Santan gum give all of those
ingredients a thorough mix with a spoon
and grab an immersion blender an
immersion blender isn't necessary here
but it mixes all the ingredients by far
the best and limits foam formation in
comparison to other methods you don't
want some bites of ice cream that are
super super sweet and others that taste
just like milk or even worse all the
sweetener is sitting at the bottom of
the Pint like this video now take the
immersion blender insert it into the
milk tilt it on an angle and start
mixing while that is mixing slowly pour
in the dry ingredients a little bit at a
time until they get sucked in by the
immersion blender once Incorporated add
more dry ingredients and repeat until
everything is fully mixed in then mix
for another 90 seconds pour the mixture
into a pint label the top and freeze for
24 hours when when it is time to eat
place the Frozen slab of chocolate onto
a cutting board and chop into bite-sized
chunks the contrast of small chips with
bigger chips will add a better texture
and mouth feel to this ice cream put
them into a plastic bag and back in the
freezer and move quick because the
chocolate will start melting almost
instantly once out of the freezer then
take your pint and run it under hot
water for 1 minute add the pint to the
creamy and blend on the sorbet function
after the creamy does its thing grab a
knife and make a hole in the middle of
the Pint only now should you grab your
chocolate or else it might melt before
you can add it to the ice cream into the
hole add 30 G and stuff the chocolate
pieces in place the ice cream you took
out back on top and spread it out add
the pint to the creamy and use the mix
in setting you now have a perfect
tasting mint chocolate chip ice cream
with pieces of chocolate in every bite
there is nothing that screams childhood
memories like an Oreo McFlurry so I knew
this needed to be made ASAP we will
start with a high-sided container on a
scale and add 430 G 1% milk and 4.2 G
vanilla extract you may be asking why I
use 1% milk here and not other milk
variations for each recipe I went
through and tried whole milk 2% 1% and
fat-free versions of each flavor this is
what I thought worked best on a calorie
to taste ratio then into another cup we
will add one scoop or 32.4 G vanilla
weight protein it is surprisingly hard
to find a good tasting vanilla protein
and it is crucial for these re recipes
or your ice cream will taste like booty
cheddar gorilla min's vanilla ice cream
flavor tastes fabulous is my go-to when
I need a vanilla way protein and you can
get 10% off by using my code E4 CM if
you don't use gorilla mines just make
sure your protein tastes topnotch we
will finish off the dry ingredients with
20 G urethral half a gram of salt and a
half gram of zanan gum mix the dry
ingredients together and like the first
recipe slowly mix in the dry ingredients
until dissolved and mix for an
additional night 90 seconds add to a
pint label it and freeze for 24 hours
when you want a cream take your pint and
run it under hot water for 1 minute all
three of these recipes were in my
cookbook not minutes before this video
came out but weeks they have been
getting great reviews alongside all 150
other recipes join the thousands who
have used them to lose weight and get
new recipes early by clicking the link
in the pin comment and use code E4 CM
for 10% off the book load the pine up
into the creamy and hit the light ice
cream button the light ice cream button
makes a soft serve like consistency
which is exactly what we need for a
McFlurry once it is done we will take a
butter knife and make a hole about 1 in
in diameter in the middle of the Pint
pull the cream out and it is time to
load in our mixings for an authentic
McFlurry it is important that the Oreo
cookie pieces stay crunchy and have
little pieces and bigger pieces spread
throughout like my cookies and cream
recipe from last year I tried several
different ways of making this work I
found the best way to do this was to use
mini Oreos for some reason maybe because
the cookie is a little bit thicker they
don't break down as much during the
mixing setting so take 28 G of mini
Oreos and fill the gaping hole up cover
the Oreos with the plated ice cream
spread it out load it back into the
creamy and hit the mixing setting during
this time I will take 11 G of mini Oreos
chop them up and mix them together so
the cookie crumbs stick to the filling
once the creamy is finished let's top
our ice cream with half the mini Oreos
and start
eating why only half once I am about a
third of the way through I like to put
another fresh layer of Oreos down so we
have chunks of Oreos in every bite this
makes sure it truly tastes like a
McFlurry from start to finish hits every
spot baby cookie dough ice cream is top
three in everyone's list so this one is
a must here my creamy boy you love the
cream if you've watched the channel you
know I've released a cookie dough before
but it was important for this cookie
dough to be more dense so you got dough
chunks in each bite of ice cream for
this reason chocolate chip cookie
dough so into a large bowl we will add
90 G allpurpose flour 48.6 G vanilla we
protein and 1.5 G of salt give
everything a quick whisk and place
another large bowl on a scale and add 21
G of butter place the butter in the
microwave for 30 seconds to a minute or
until melted then add one egg one egg
yolk 4.2 G vanilla extract 24 G
granulated urethral and 24 G brown sugar
urethral if you watched my protein
cookie dough video you know how I feel
about eating raw eggs but you could also
buy pasteurized eggs or SV your own eggs
if you would like mix all the wet
ingredients together until well combined
then add about 1/3 of the dry
ingredients combine the two and then add
another third of the dry ingredients at
this point we need to switch over to a
rubber spatula because the dough will
become too thick the Whisk and
everything will just get stuck when
everything is smooth add the last bit of
dry ingredients and mix until your
forearm has a full pump the dough should
be thick with three C's so if you don't
have a full forearm pump the ingredients
aren't fully mixed in the last thing we
need to add is 21 G of mini chocolate
chips and combine the cookie dough has
Peak flavor after 24 hours which is why
we did this now so get it into a
container and refrigerate per usual for
our ice cream we will get a high-sided
container on a scale ale and add 430 G
2% milk and 4.2 G vanilla extract then
into a measuring cup we will add 32.4 G
vanilla protein 10 G urethral half a
gram of salt and a half gr Santan gum
mix the dry ingredients together using
an immersion blender slowly add the dry
ingredients and once they have dissolved
mix for another 90 seconds add the
liquid ice cream to a pint and freeze 24
hours later grab the Pint and run it
under hot water for 60 seconds load it
up and hit the sorbet function once it
finishes grab the Pint and make a 1-in
hole in the middle take the cookie dough
out of the fridge put it on a scale and
add 50 g to the Pint cover the cookie
dough with cream load it back up and hit
the mixing setting you now have the
perfect taste and texture of cookie
dough ice cream with cookie dough in
every bite look at all that goddamn
cookie dough for everyone God I love it
so much yeah every one of these pints
has at least 50 g of protein and tastes
just like its higher calories
counterpart while having half the
calories having the freedom to add
whatever mixins you want to a solid ice
cream base gives you endless ice cream
flavor possibilities in this video here
I show you how to make three versions of
vanilla ice cream from good to best that
will unlock any potential flavor you
would like to make until next time
deuces